[Music]
hi guys my name is marcel and you out
there struggling with drawing
perspective and i'll promise you after
you've watched this video you'll at
least somewhat get the hang of how to
draw this because today i'll show you
guys how to draw humans in perspective
like sir as always i gave it my all to
make this video as easy to understand as
possible with animations 3d models
references and even a draw along part
where you and i draw perspective
together when i did this draw along part
in my posing video you all loved it so i
thought we could draw something together
in this video as well so why not grab a
pencil and the piece of paper
and let's get go
[Music]
now let's start
from the start i think it's the classic
beginner mistake to draw your character
and object in perspective along with all
of the details uh yeah maybe don't do
that everyone and even pros start out
with basic shapes because some character
designs out there
it can get pretty complicated to draw
so let's take it down a notch and draw
this together as easy as possible
we're not drawing any details right from
the start like we do in all of my videos
we're using some basic shapes first
here you have an overview to make things
easier we're dividing this basic body
with 5 lines this is up to preference i
just like to use 5 lines so it doesn't
get too complicated
and this is all you need for starters
let's keep this overview on this side so
we can always reference it because we're
now going to draw a human in perspective
you can draw along if you want
also you don't have to draw very small
take some space if you wanna it's easier
to erase this way
the first thing that i'm drawing is the
dynamic line to determine which way my
character is facing this is nothing new
you know this guideline from my previous
tutorials already
next up though we are drawing these
sections we divided our character
[Music]
now don't forget that those sections are
not supposed to look flat they're in 3d
so make sure the gaps are getting
smaller and smaller just like they would
in an actual 3d space
[Music]
and now all that's left to do is to now
place our human building blocks that
we've established before
now that's easier said than done because
this is probably not gonna work out
first try for you you have to get a
feeling for this drawing in perspective
can get pretty tricky so don't get
discouraged if your first drawings don't
look like mine from the very get-go
also don't draw these shapes
half-heartedly that's because you need
to make sure that you're drawing this
correctly after all this is your base
and your base needs to be correct if
it's not your drawing will look crooked
later on it's just like building a house
if the foundation is uneven the whole
damn thing will collapse in on itself
don't worry you can always check if
everything's correct by checking if the
joints are about the same height
and that's pretty much it for starters
to this basic body you can now add
things like for example clothing muscles
or even other details because now you've
made sure that everything's proportioned
correctly
now i'm not going to explain to you how
to draw every single muscle though
however if you're interested i have
videos that give you an overview on
human anatomy and how to draw human
faces in perspective they are all
uploaded to my channel if you want to
watch them
also this is kind of self-explanatory
but of course this method works with the
other way around as well in case you
want to draw a human from for example
below
[Music]
you just have to adjust the gaps so that
now the sections on the upper part are
smaller
and speaking of gaps if you want to draw
some extreme perspective you can
experiment by making the gaps smaller or
larger
but maybe you just started out which is
why you would still need to practice
perspective before you can draw some
extreme views
but luckily i have some tips for
practicing as well
[Music]
the best way to practice this is by
looking up reference images i can
suggest looking up a darker stalker on
deviantart she has some really good ones
you could use
then you can use the overview from this
tutorial
right after you've liked this video then
you can divide your reference pose and
draw a basic body just like we did
before after you've subscribed to this
channel and then you can add some
muscles and clothing
after you've given me all of your money
on patreon what's also super helpful to
use is 3d models
stop stop no no i'm aware i'm aware not
everyone's a fan of that i'm the witch
but 3d models are great because you can
adjust them in any way you like i'm not
saying that you have to trace it or
whatever i'm just saying that if you
want to practice drawing perspective
this makes for some very good reference
material
now would you mind
taking that away
please
i mean it's the same thing as using one
of those creepy wood puppet dolls but
just
objectively but in my humble opinion
this beats searching hours on end for a
suitable reference when you can just
make the reference yourself also if
you're interested in what tablet or kind
of software i'm using for this i have a
complete list over on my website
now this was the easy way to practice it
but if you're an aspiring comic or manga
artist you now have to take it up a
notch believe me i know what i'm talking
about i had to learn this the hard way
[Music]
because when drawing your characters in
an actual scenario like manga or comic
panels you need to use a vanishing point
you can imagine your vanishing point
like a magnet where all of your division
guidelines from before are pointing
towards
this is absolutely important because
that's the only way to get the height
and dimensions of your character's right
you can use these guidelines to measure
where characters in the distance are
supposed to stand also like i said you
could use this method to figure out how
tall they are
and to make things a bit more believable
yes this also goes for characters that
are standing sideways
but since you'll need a second vanishing
point for that things are only going to
get more complicated from here
[Music]
if you still want to learn more about
vanishing points and drawing things like
objects or buildings in perspective i've
got you covered there are already
tutorials on my channel about basically
everything so if you still struggle with
a topic you can check out my other
videos this also includes vanishing
points like always this video took me a
lot of time to animate and edit i'd
appreciate if you'd be supporting me to
make more tutorials like this what do
you want to see next though i thought
about making a video about inking your
artworks you guys know i love inking and
hatching to death i also thought about
making videos about coloring or digital
art but those are literally the most
unpopular videos on my channel which is
why i'm probably not gonna make more
videos like that anymore anyways thanks
so much for watching i'll see you guys
on my next video or in the meantime on
instagram and twitter goodbye
[Music]
[Applause]
you